Guide to Emory University Catalogs, etc. Cubb.00114
Cubberley Education Library
Emory University (formerly: Emory College)
1896-1979
Cubberley Education Library
Cubb.00114
165 item(s)
Founded in Oxford, Georgia in 1836 as Emory College. Moved to Atlanta and chartered as Emory University in 1915. Affiliated with the United Methodist Church.
Georgia
- Emory College, 1896-1897; 1 item(s) Catalog for 1896/97
- Emory University, 1919-1979; 164 item(s) Catalogs for 1919/20-1923/24, 1925/26-1936/37, 1938/39-1939/40, 1941/42, 1944/45, 1946/47-1948/49, 1951/52, 1955/56, 1963/64 Special Catalog Issue: 1946
  - Emory University School of Medicine, 1912-1970; 47 item(s); Located in Atlanta, Georgia. Founded in 1854 as Atlanta Medical College. In 1898 merged with Southern Medical College to become Atlanta College of Physicians and Surgeons. In 1913 merged with Atlanta School of Medicine to form Atlanda Medical College. In 1915 tranferred holdings to Emory to become Emory University School of Medicine.
    Medical colleges
    - Atlanta College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1901-1913; 3 item(s) Announcements for 1901/02 & 1911/12 Catalog for 1912/13
    - Southern Medical College, 1895-1897; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1895/96-1896/97
    - Emory University School of Medicine, 1915-1979; 42 item(s) Bulletins for 1915-1916 Catalogs for 1919/20-1931/32, 1933/34-1937/38, 1940/41-1942/43, 1945/46-1946/47, 1948/49-1956/57, 1958/59-1961/62, 1977/78-1978/79 Announcements for 1964/65-1966/67
  - Emory University School of Law (Lamar School of Law), 1920-1969; 36 item(s) Announcements for 1920/21-1928/29, 1930/31-1941/42, 1943/44-1944/45, 1946/47-1949/50, 1951/52-1956/57, 1959/60, 1966/67, 1968/69
    Law schools
  - Emory Summer Session, 1921; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1921
  - Emory College, 1965-1979; 4 item(s) Bulletins for 1965/66-1966/67, 1976/77, 1978/79
  - Emory at Valdosta, 1946-1948; 2 item(s) Catalogs for 1946/47-1947/48
  - Emory University College of Arts and Sciences, 1949-1965; 9 item(s) Announcements for 1949/50-1950/51, 1953/54, 1955/56, 1957/58, 1959/60-1960/61, 1962/63, 1964/65
  - Emory University Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1956-1979; 11 item(s) 1956/57, 1960/61-1962/63, 1964/65-1967/69, 1970/71, 1972/73, 1975/76, 1978/79
  - Emory University Division of Librarianship, 1954-1969; 9 item(s) Bulletins for 1954/55-1956/57, 1958/59, 1964/65-1968/69
    Library Schools
  - Emory University Candler School of Theology, 1965-66; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1965/66
    Theological seminaries
  - Emory University Internship Master of Arts in Teaching Program, 1968-1970; 2 item(s) Brochures for 1968/69-1969/70
    Teachers colleges
  - Emory University School of Nursing, 1966-67; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1966/67
    Nursing schools
  - Report From the President of Emory University in Atlanta, December, 1959; 1 item(s) Report from December, 1959
  - Emory University School of Dentistry, 1966-1969; 3 item(s) Bulletins for 1966/67-1969
    Dental schools
  - Emory University School of Business Administration, 1958-1968; 2 item(s) Bulletins for 1958/60, 1966/68
    Business schools
  - Emory University Graduate Institute of the Liberal Arts, 1953-1967; 5 item(s) Bulletins for 1953-1955, 1966/67
  - Emory University Graduate School, 1954-55; 1 item(s) Bulletin for 1954/55